

EXPERIENCE

Business News Media ZAO, Moscow, Russia — Senior Software Engineer

SEPTEMBER 2018 - PRESENT

Designed and implemented comments service via WebSockets (Go, Ruby, Postgresql, RabbitMQ, Redis).

Proposed a way to change the client requests logic decreasing DB load by 21%.

Implemented functionality to meet the requirements of new laws passed by the Federal Tax Service (VAT rate changed, a new type of receipt put into circulation) (Ruby, MSSql remote procedures, PostgreSQL).

Refactored legacy code reducing the time the users spend on registration by 16%.

BillBored Inc, St John's, Canada — Software Developer

FEBRUARY 2018 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Implemented functional testing for an SDK in Elixir (ExUnit, VCR, XML-based third parties APIs).

Unlimited Technologies, Moscow, Russia — Software Developer

MAY 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

Designed and implemented a push service via FCM and APNS integrated with all client platforms. (Elixir, Erlang, Postgresql, Kafka, Redis).

Business Car LLC (Toyota Tsusho Corporation subsidiary), Moscow, Russia — *Software Developer*

JULY 2015 - APRIL 2016

Designed and implemented a questionnaire section of the inner CRM system decreasing the preservice time by 15%. (Ruby, RoR).

Forward Media Group, Moscow, Russia — Advertising Sales Director

JANUARY 2009 - JULY 2015

Managed and implemented ad sales plan covering all production and editorial costs of the original Russian glossy magazine (Story magazine).

VI, Moscow, Russia — Advertising Sales Director

2003 - 2008

As part of a team launched HELLO! Magazine in Russia. The ad sales plan was outstripped by 30% in the first year and by 15% in the second one.

Participated in annual marketing events (Baselworld, SIHH) that increased the part of the luxury segment in ad budget by 60%.

${\bf Computerra\ Publishing\ House,}\ {\bf Moscow,}\ {\bf Russia-Marketing\ and}\ {\bf \it Advertising}\ {\bf \it Manager}$

2003

 $Elaborating\ advertising\ and\ promotional\ materials\ about\ the\ company's\ projects,\ ad\ sales.$

SUMMARY

4+ years of experience in Golang, Ruby, Elixir, and Erlang programming. I'm a self-taught person with experience in designing and implementing software. Proven ability to write maintainable, quality code covered with tests. Strong yearning for perfect results, based on elegant solutions and latest technologies. Used to working under pressure to meet tight deadlines and handling unpredicted changes.

I also have 10+ years of wide experience in Advertising & Sales with major Publishing Russian companies on top positions with strong skills in starting new projects.

SKILLS

Golang, Ruby, Elixir, Erlang, PostgreSQL, Cassandra, Mnesia, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Redis, Memcached, ElasticSearch, Docker, Git

EDUCATION

Bauman Moscow State Technical University, Moscow

2016 - 2019

B.S. in Computer Software Engineering

Lomonosov Moscow State University, Moscow

1999 - 2004

M.S. in Developmental and Child Psychology

PROJECTS

Vedomosti — print and online newspaper services (vedomosti.ru, hbr-russia.ru).

Express — enterprise messaging app.

Business Car — CRM system spanning all departments of Toyota dealers in Russia.